now let's say if we have
a 10 kilogram block
next to another
10 kilogram block
and let's say that these two blocks
are separated by distance of 10 meters
and let's say the axis of rotation
is placed at the center of mass of the
system
so each block
is 5 meters away
from the axis of rotation
what is the inertia
of this system
the total inertia of the system
is going to be the inertia of every
point
so we got the moment of inertia for the
first object we'll call it m1 so it's m1
r1 squared plus the moment of inertia
for the second object
so it's going to be 10 kilograms
times r which is 5. r is the distance
between the axis of rotation
and the mass of the object
and the other ones could be the same
it's 10 times 5 squared
5 squared is 25
and 10 times 25 is 250 so 250 plus 250
is 500
so the inertia of the system when the
axis of rotation is at the center of
mass
is 500
kilograms
times square meters
now what is the inertia of the system
if we move the axis of rotation
to the center of the 10 kilogram mass so
let's say if we move it
five meters to the left
what is the new inertia of the system
so let's find out
so the new inertia
is going to be the sum
of the moment of each
inertia for each object
so we could use the same equation
so m1 is still 10 however r1 is zero
because the first mass is directly at
the axis of rotation
the second mass
is 10 meters
away from the new axis of rotation
so 10 squared is 100 and 10 times 100 is
a thousand
so the new inertia
is one thousand
kilograms times square meters
now there's another way in which you can
get this answer
and that's used in the parallel axis
theorem
the parallel axis theorem allows us to
calculate the new inertia value
if we have the original inertia
where the axis of rotation
passes through the center of mass
using this equation
now keep in mind this only works if the
new axis
is parallel to the original axis
and if the original axis has to pass
through the center of mass and this
system has to be symmetrical notice that
these masses are the same if they're
different it's not going to work
so we have the old inertia value that's
m represents the mass of the whole
system which is 10 plus 10 so that's 20.
and d
is the displacement of the axis of
rotation
so we displaced it by five meters
five squared is twenty five
and twenty five times twenty
is five hundred
so the new inertia value is 500 plus 500
which is a thousand
kilograms times square meters
which is the same as this answer
so now you know how to use the parallel
axis theorem to calculate the new
inertia of a system
now let's try another example
so this time we're going to have a
system with four masses
as opposed to two masses
so each block
has a mass of 4 kilograms
and what i want you to do in this
problem
is i want you to calculate the inertia
of the system
first
when the axis of rotation
passes through the center of mass of the
system
so each of these four kilogram blocks
they're equally distant from
the axis of rotation
so they're all five meters
away from it
so feel free to pause the video
and calculate
the total inertia of the system
so the inertia of the system as it
passes through the center of mass
is going to be the sum
of the individual
moments of inertia of each object in
this
system
so it's the sum of m r squared
so each block has a mass of four
and an r value of five meters they're
five minutes away from the axis of
rotation so that's for one block
so for each of the four identical blocks
to get the total inertia let's multiply
by four
so 5 squared is 25 25 times 4 is 100 and
100 times 4 is 400
so the inertia is 400 kilograms times
meter squares
now let's move the axis of rotation
to the left
and we're going to move it by a distance
of 9 meters
to the left
so what is the new inertia of the system
and use both methods to get the answer
so to calculate the new inertia
it's going to be
so this object
is 4 meters away from the new center of
mass
9 minus 5 is 4. and so we have two
objects that's four meters away from it
so it's going to be two times the mass
of those objects
two times four gives us the total mass
of the two objects
and they're each four meters away from
the axis of rotation
now these two masses
they're 14 meters away five plus five
plus four
or you can simply say
five plus nine that's going to be 14
meters
so we have two of those masses
each with a mass of four kilograms
and they're 40 meters apart from the new
axis of rotation
4 squared is 16 times 4 that's 64
times 2
so this is 128
and then 14 squared times 4 times 2
fifteen sixty eight
so therefore
the new inertia of the system is one
thousand six hundred ninety six
kilograms times square meters
now let's confirm this answer using the
parallel axis term
so the new inertia
is equal to the old one
where the axis of rotation passes
through the center of mass
plus
md squared
so the original inertia was 400
the mass of the whole system is 4 plus 4
plus 4 plus 4.
so that's 16 kilograms
and the axis of rotation has been
shifted 9 meters
and don't forget to square it
9 squared is 81.
81 times 16 is 1296
and 1296 plus 400
is 16
so as you can see the answer is the same
so now you have a second example that
illustrates the use of the parallel axis
theorem
now let's move on to a third example
so if we have a very thin rod
where the axis of rotation passes
through the center of mass
and let's say l
represents the length of that rod
the inertia
of this system
is 1 over 12
ml squared
now let's say if we have the same rod
with the same mass and the mass is
distributed evenly
throughout this rod
but if we move the axis of rotation
to the edge of the rod
then the inertia of the system changes
it's now
one-third
ml squared
what i want you to do
is i want you to prove
that this equation is true
using the parallel axis theorem starting
from this one
so this is the inertia
when the axis of rotation passes through
the center of mass
and our goal is to calculate the new
inertia
so it's going to be the old one
plus
m d squared
so the old inertia
is this equation
it's 1 over 12
ml squared
plus md squared
so
the new axis of rotation
has been shifted
this way
and since l is the length of the rod the
new axis have been shifted
one half of the length of the rod
so d
is going to be one half of l
so 1 squared is 1 2 squared is 4.
so we got 1 4
ml squared
now what we need to do is get common
denominators in order to add these two
fractions so i'm going to multiply this
by 3 over 3. so this is going to be one
over twelve
m l squared plus three over twelve
m l squared
one over twelve plus three over twelve
is four over twelve ml squared
and 12 divided by 4 is 3 so 4 over 12 is
1 over 3.
so therefore we get the same answer
you